
[
  {
    "question": "What type of landforms DO NOT make up Ancient Greece ",
    "choice1": "desert",
    "choice2": "peninsula",
    "choice3": "mountains",
    "choice4": "islands",
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the first civilization to arise in Ancient Greece?",
    "choice1": "gargoyles",
    "choice2": "minoans",
    "choice3": "indians",
    "choice4": "nobles",
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Mycenaen civilization collapse?",
    "choice1": "dried up",
    "choice2": "glaciers",
    "choice3": "earthquakes",
    "choice4": "ice age",
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Mycenaen civilization collapse?",
    "choice1": "glaciers ",
    "choice2": "no food source",
    "choice3": "ice age",
    "choice4": "civil war",
    "answer": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "What were important economic activites for the Ancient Greeks",
    "choice1": "trading and fishing",
    "choice2": "selling and buying",
    "choice3": "playing and fighting",
    "choice4": "walking and selling",
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was in charge of the Greek city-states?",
    "choice1": "the priests",
    "choice2": "the nobels",
    "choice3": "the Gods",
    "choice4": "the people",
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "A piece of land nearly surrounded by water",
    "choice1": "island",
    "choice2": "colony",
    "choice3": "peninsula",
    "choice4": "continent",
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Someone who writes or performs epic poems or stories about heroes and their deeds",
    "choice1": "author",
    "choice2": "scribe",
    "choice3": "writer",
    "choice4": "Bard",
    "answer": 4
  },
  {
    "question": "A group of people living in a new territory who have ties to their homeland",
    "choice1": "colony",
    "choice2": "tribe",
    "choice3": "team",
    "choice4": "neighborhood",
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "A Greek City-State",
    "choice1": "State",
    "choice2": "Polis",
    "choice3": "County",
    "choice4": "Country",
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "A gathering place; marketplace in Ancient Greece",
    "choice1": "home",
    "choice2": "meeting area",
    "choice3": "Agora",
    "choice4": "territory",
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "A group of armed foot soldiers in ancient Greece arranged close together in rows",
    "choice1": "army",
    "choice2": "platoon",
    "choice3": "infantry",
    "choice4": "Phalanx",
    "answer": 4
  }
  
]
  
